CONTACT INFORMATION Rm 614, Kelvin Building University of Glasgow Glasgow, G12 8QQ United Kingdom

Work: +44 (0)14133 08855 Web: www.pauljwright.co.uk Email: paul.wright@glasgow.ac.uk Publication List: SAO/NASA ADS

RESEARCH INTERESTS My interests range from stellar to solar physics; my main interests lie in the heating of the solar atmosphere, including active regions and loops. I have expertise in analysis of data from Kepler, SDO/AIA, Hinode/EIS, Hinode/XRT, and NuSTAR's heliophysics observations. In addition, I am currently modelling coronal light-curves using the EBTEL (Enthalpy Based Thermal Evolution of Loops) hydrodynamic code.

**EDUCATION** 

#### University of Glasgow, Glasgow, UK

2014 – present (expected 2018)

Ph.D. Solar Physics

Thesis Topic: The Energetics of Small Flares and Brightenings Advisers: Dr Iain G. Hannah, Dr Alexander MacKinnon

#### University of Southampton, Southampton, UK

2010 - 2014

MPhys Astrophysics with a year abroad

First-class honours (1:1)

Adviser: Professor Malcolm Coe

#### Harvard University/Harvard-Smithsonian CfA, Cambridge, MA

2013 - 2014

MPhys Astrophysics with a year abroad

Thesis Topic: Superflare Rates of Solar-Like Stars Advisers: Dr Steven H. Saar, Dr Jeremy J. Drake

CURRENT ACADEMIC APPOINTMENT

### Affiliate Staff Member, University of Glasgow SUPA School of Physics and Astronomy

2017 - present

**PREVIOUS** ACADEMIC APPOINTMENTS

#### Post-Graduate Research Assistant, University of Glasgow

2014 - 2017

SUPA School of Physics and Astronomy

Project: The Energetics of Small Flares and Brightenings

- Analysed observations of the Sun with *NuSTAR*, a telescope not designed for heliophysics. These observations are the most sensitive of their kind and have resulted in numerous, wideranging highly-collaborative peer-reviewed publications.
- Analysed non-flaring coronal time-series in pursuit of signatures of the coronal heating mechanism. Techniques included time-lag analysis (cross-correlation), Fourier analysis, wavelet analysis, and local intermittency measure (LIM).
- Studied the temperature distribution of the solar atmosphere through the recovery of an illposed inverse problem (the differential emission measure, DEM) using techniques such as Tikhonov regularisation, Markov-Chain Monte Carlo, and sparsity.
- The press-release image produced from the NuSTAR observations analysed in Wright et al. 2017 was published by multiple news outlets, and is one of the five iconic images from NuSTAR's first five years in space.

Collaborators: Dr Iain Hannah, Dr Alexander MacKinnon

### Visiting Researcher, NASA Goddard Space Flight Center (GSFC)

2016

Heliophysics Science Division

 Worked on the possibility of implementing DEM maps in the Helioviewer project, and their usefulness as an input for various established analysis techniques.

Collaborators: Dr Nicholeen Viall, Dr Jack Ireland

## Research Scholar, Harvard-Smithsonian Center for Astrophysics (CfA)

2013 - 2014

Solar and Stellar X-Ray Group

- Designed and implemented a sophisticated stellar flare detection routine for long-cadence (30 mins) Kepler data obtained from a proprietary set of spectroscopically verified solar-type stars in three open clusters.
- This work has had coverage by Science, and The Smithsonian Magazine.

Collaborators: Dr Steven Saar, Dr Søren Meibom, Dr Jeremy Drake, Dr Vinay Kashyap

D	III M I A I C 'I D M CI I I I I I I I I I I I I I I I I I	. C II I		
REFEREED JOURNAL PUBLICATIONS	[1] Marsh, A. J., Smith, D. M., Glesener, L. et al 2017. First NuSTAR Limits on Quiet Sun Hard X-Ray Transient Events, ApJ (accepted)			
	[2] Wang, J., Simões, P. J. A., Jeffrey, N. L. S. et al 2017. Observations of Reconnection Flows in a Flare on The Solar Disk, ApJL, 847, L1			
	[3] <b>Wright, P. J.</b> , Hannah, I. G., Grefenstette, B. W., et al 2017. Microflare Heating of a Solar Active Region Observed with NuSTAR, Hinode/XRT, and SDO/AIA, ApJ, 844, 132			
	[4] Kuhar, M., Krucker, S., Hannah, I. G., et al 2017. Evidence of Significant Energy Input in the Late Phase of a Solar Flare from NuSTAR X-ray Observations, ApJ, 835, 6			
FIRST AUTHOR PUBLICATIONS IN PREPERATION	[5] Wright, P. J., Hannah, I. G., Viall, N. M., et al			
	[6] Wright, P. J., Saar, S. H., Meibom, S., et al			
CONFERENCES, WORKSHOPS, & SCHOOLS	Invited Oral Presentations  ISSI Team Meeting: Coronal Nanoflares, Bern, CH  Harvard-Smithsonian Center for Astrophysics, Cambridge, MA, USA	2016 2014		
	Oral/ePoster Presentations			
	Solar Physics Division Meeting (SPD/AAS), Portland, OR, USA	2017		
	Coronal Loops Workshop VIII, Palermo, Sicily, IT	2017		
	Living with a Star (SDO/LWS) Workshop, Burlington, VT, USA	2016		
	Hinode 10, Nagoya, JP	2016		
	National Astronomy Meeting 2016, Nottingham, UK	2016		
	Hinode 9, Belfast, UK	2015		
	Glasgow-Cambridge Flare Workshop, Glasgow, UK	2015		
	Poster Presentations			
	European Solar Physics Meeting (ESPM), Budapest, HU	2017		
	Solar Physics Division Meeting (SPD/AAS), Portland, OR, USA	2017		
	Living with a Star (SDO/LWS) Workshop, Burlington, VT, USA	2016 2015		
	Coronal Loops Workshop VII, Cambridge, UK NAM 2015, Llandudno, UK	2015		
	223rd AAS Meeting, National Harbor, MD, USA	2013		
	Schools Attended			
	CESRA Radio Summer School 2015, Glasgow, UK	2015		
	STFC Advanced Summer School in Solar Physics, Dundee, UK	2014		
	Conferences/Workshops Attended			
	NuSTAR Heliophysics Workshop (remote participation), Berkeley, CA, USA	2017		
	SUPA Cormack Astronomy Meeting, Edinburgh, UK	2015		
	RAS Discussion Meeting: Results from IRIS, London, UK	2015		
	SUPA Cormack Astronomy Meeting, Edinburgh, UK	2014		
	1st Space Glasgow Research Conference, Glasgow, UK	2014		
AWARDS AND	University of Glasgow	2015		
GRANTS	Solar Physics Division Meeting (SPD/AAS) Student Poster Award	2017		
TOTAL: £7000	Solar Physics Division Meeting (SPD/AAS) Studentship Award Coronal Loops Workshop VIII Travel Award	2017 2017		
	National Astronomical Observatory of Japan Travel Award	2017		
	Hinode 9 Travel Award	2015		
	European Space Agency/Cambridge Philosophical Society Travel Award	2015		
	Harvard University/Smithsonian Astrophysical Observatory			
	233rd AAS Travel Grant	2014		
	University of Southampton			
	Research Scholarship	2013		
	Summer Studentship Grant	2013		
	ı			

TEACHING

**University of Glasgow** 

TEACHING	Astronomy 1 Tutorial Demonstrator	2016 - 2017		
	Supervised students, and marked first-year astronomy problem sets.			
	Physics Pre-University Summer School	2015		
	Taught at a pre-university school for students entering first year. <b>Astronomy 3/4 (Honours) Laboratory Demonstrator</b>	2015 - 2016		
	Demonstrated, supervised, and marked a number of final-year research			
	topics such as asteroid light curves, and solar limb darkening.	i projects covering		
MEMBERSHIPS	NuSTAR Heliophysics Working Group, Member	2015 – present		
	International Space Science Institute (ISSI), Young Scientist Member	2015 – present		
	Member of Paola Testa's ISSI Team: New Diagnostics of Particle Acceleration	on in Solar Coronal		
	Nanoflares from Chromospheric Observations and Modeling  Boyal Astronomical Society, PAS Follows	2014 present		
	Royal Astronomical Society, RAS Fellow	2014 – present		
COMMUNITY	Nature Communications, Reviewer	2017 – present		
INVOLVEMENT	Glasgow Astronomy & Astrophysics Group Meeting, Organiser	2017		
	CESRA Radio Summer School, Volunteer Organiser	2015		
SCIENTIFIC	Glasgow Science Centre, Demonstrator	2016		
OUTREACH	British Science Week, Demonstrator	2016		
	Institute of Physics: Women and Girls in Science, Demonstrator Scottish Television (STV), Guest Presenter	2016 2015		
	World Wide Telescope, Ambassador	2013 – 2014		
	BBC Stargazing Live, Demonstrator	2013 – 2014		
	So'ton Astrodome, Demonstrator	2012		
	BBC Bang Goes The Theory Roadshow, Demonstrator	2012		
	<b>UK Solar Physics (UKSP) Nuggets</b> , concise, easy-to-read science articles 84. The first <i>NuSTAR</i> microflare	2017		
	Hinode/XRT Picture of the Week (XPOW)			
	The First Microflare Observations with <i>Hinode/XRT &amp; NuSTAR</i>	2017		
PERSONAL PROJECTS	ColourBlind, A repository for colour-blind-friendly colour tables.	Citations: 1		
Professional	Coursera, Inc. (MOOC Platform)			
DEVELOPMENT	Using Coursera.org, a massive open online course (MOOC) platform, to take specializations (a series			
	of related courses and a final capstone project) offered by accredited universities	s to further develop		
	skills and understanding in a wide range of computer science topics.			
	Data Science, Johns Hopkins University	2017 – present		
	Nine-course (plus capstone) introduction to data science.	-		
	Mastering Software Development in R, Johns Hopkins University	2017 – present		
	Four-course (plus capstone) specialization providing riguourous training			
	<b>Statistics with R</b> , Duke University Four-course (plus capstone) specialization providing further training in R	2017 – present		
	statistics.	t, with emphasis on		
	Big Data, UC San Diego	2017 – present		
	Five-course (plus capstone) introduction to big data using Hadoop with I	MapReduce, Spark,		
	Pig and Hive.	2015		
	Machine Learning, University of Washington	2017 – present		
	Three-course (plus capstone) introduction to Machine Learning.	2017 present		
	Graphic Design, CalArts Four-course (plus capstone) introduction the fundamental skills required	2017 – present		
	cated graphic design.	a to make sopmon-		
	o			

PROFESSIONAL DEVELOPMENT (CONT.)	edx, Inc. (MOOC Platform)  Introduction to Computer Science (CS50x), Harvard University 2017 – present An introduction to the intellectual enterprises of computer science and the art of programming including languages such as C, and SQL.
TECHNICAL SKILLS:	Computing: C, Python, R (caret, ggplot2, knitr), SQL, CRAN, IDL, ETeX, git, GitHub, Hadoop (MapReduce, Spark, Pig, Hive), Linux/Unix, Mac OSX, Microsoft Windows, Bash, Microsoft Office, Adobe Creative Cloud, Keynote, Wordpress, Shiny, GoogleVis, and Plotly, HTML, CSS, Javascript
	General: Data Analysis, Data Visualization, Interdisciplinary Collaboration, Public Speaking, Statistics, Teaching, Writing (Technical & Lay)
More Information	More information and auxiliary documents can be found at http://www.pauljwright.co.uk, on ResearchGate, and GitHub.